Let's get started with Day 5 for the month of October
Hi everyone, I'm Steve Sarese
今年度のテーマは英語でつながる船の旅
今月向かうのはアイルランドです
ということで早速一緒に旅をする会話パートナーを呼びましょう
この方です
Hi everyone, I'm Nora Kennedy
I'll be your conversation partner
Welcome back to Eikaiwa Time Trial, Nora.
Thanks, Steve.
So we're going to Ireland, your home country.
Yes, very exciting.
アイルランドといえば何を思い浮かべますか?
I think people think of Ireland as being a bit like Hokkaido.
It's green, the rivers are clean, the sea is beautiful,
and it's a really great place to enjoy nature.
I see.
And how about food?
Ah, food is Ireland's speciality.
We make amazing cheese, like blue cheese,
Casual blue cheese is really good.
We make lots of butter, amazing lamb, beef.
Irish food is excellent, and oysters, of course.
Woo!
That's perfect, because, Nora,
this month, we're talking about food.
Great, my favorite topic.
Let's get started.
Taiwa Karaoke
ラジオを通して英語で模擬会話をする実践的なトレーニングです
早速今日の会話の場面を確認しましょう
今日はアイルランデと向かうクルーズ船で開催されるお寿司のランチパーティーに参加します
It's a special kind of sushi. We make it ourselves. 手巻き寿司
今回は野良さんと手巻き寿司を作ります
So, could you help me with it?
野良さんに手巻き寿司の作り方や 日本の食材について上手に説明しましょう
Did you picture the situation?
では野良さんの英語の問いかけに対して ポーズの間に英語で返答してみましょう
So, try to have a seven-turn conversation as we have lunch on the cruise.
Ready, start!
Oh, hello! Are you going to the special sushi lunch, too?
自分も行くと伝えましょう。どうぞ。
Alright! Today we have Teimaki Sushi.
am i saying that properly 正しく手巻き寿司を発音できていたか聞かれました
一言返しましょう
do you often make sushi at home in japan
oh here is the sushi buffet
First, we get this black, dark green, thin thing.
What do you call this?
ここでノリについてしっかり説明しましょう。どうぞ。
I see.
How much rice should I put on the nori?
Oh, I'll spread the rice out with this rice spoon?
Next, do I put soy sauce on the rice?
ご飯の上にお醤油をかけるか聞かれました
自由に答えましょう
So, now I'll put in some fish. I'll have Irish smoked salmon.
What kind of fish are you going to put in your sushi?
Time's up!
How did you do? Did you reply to each one?
それでは、野良さんと僕でこの会話をしてみます。
僕の返答をチェックして参考にしてみてください
スティーブは一つの答えを教えてくれます
行ってみましょう
おー、こんにちは
スシランチに行ってもいいですか?
ええ、一緒に行ってみましょう
いいね
今日は手巻き寿司を食べます
正しく言っていいですか?
手巻き寿司は結構いい言葉です
Do you often make sushi at home in Japan?
Not really. We usually go to our neighborhood sushi restaurant.
Oh, here is the sushi buffet.
First, we get this black, dark green, thin thing.
What do you call this?
It's called nori.
Some people call it seaweed in English, but seaweed might not be an appetizing word.
It's a kind of sea plant.
I see. How much rice should I put on the nori?
Just don't put too much rice on it. If you put too much rice on it, it will be hard to make a roll.
Oh, I'll spread the rice out with this rice spoon.
Next, do I put soy sauce on the rice?
Well, you can, but I dip it in soy sauce right before I eat it.
So, now I'll put in some fish.
I'll have Irish smoked salmon.
What kind of fish are you going to put in your sushi?
Fresh tuna or maguro.
But actually, this is minced tuna called negitoro.
Okay, good.
Did you understand our conversation?
We're talking about food, sushi.
Nora, what is your favorite sushi meta or fish?
That's an easy question.
It's scallop or hotate.
Oh, that's one of my favorites as well.
皆さんいかがですか?Do you like scallops?
それでは、最後にもう一度今日の模擬会話に挑戦です。
Do your best, everyone.
レディースタート
おー、ハロー
スシランチも行くの?
いいね
今日はテイマキスシ
正しく言うか
do you often make sushi at home in japan
oh here is the sushi buffet first we get this black dark green
thin thing what do you call this
I see. How much rice should I put on the nori?
Oh, I'll spread the rice out with this rice spoon.
Next, do I put soy sauce on the rice?
Yes.
so now i'll put in some fish i'll have irish smoked salmon
what kind of fish are you gonna put in your sushi
okay time's up you did much better the second time great job
2回目の挑戦はいかがでしたか
さて来週はついに野良さんのホームカントリー
アイルランドに到着しますよ
I'm really looking forward to showing you the Emerald Isle
エムラルドアイルというニックネームがアイルランドにありますね
And everyone get on board
And let's practice speaking together
See you next time on
英会話タントライアル
バイバイ